One day in PE, he stepped on my shoe and refused to apologize. So, filled with anger, I grabbed him and I threw him to the ground. I'd had some previous judo training. (Laughter) Our fight lasted less than two minutes, but it was a perfect reflection of the hurricane that was building inside of me as a young survivor of sexual assault and as a girl who was grappling with abandonment and exposure to violence in other spaces in my life. I was fighting him, but I was also fighting the men and boys that had assaulted my body and the culture that told me I had to be silent about it. A teacher broke up the fight and my principal called me in her office. But she didn't say, "Monique, what's wrong with you?" She gave me a moment to collect my breath and asked, "What happened?" The educators working with me led with empathy. They knew me. They knew I loved to read, they knew I loved to draw,
Un día en educación física, me pisó y se negó a disculparse. Llena de rabia, lo agarré y lo tiré contra el suelo. Había hecho judo anteriormente. (Risas) Nuestra pelea duró menos de dos minutos pero fue el reflejo perfecto del huracán que se creaba dentro de mí como joven superviviente de agresión sexual y una chica que estaba lidiando con el abandono y expuesta a la violencia en otros ámbitos de mi vida. Estaba peleando con él pero también luchaba contra los hombres y chicos que agredieron mi cuerpo y la cultura que me dijo que debía guardar silencio. Un profesor disolvió la pelea y mi directora me llamó a su oficina. Pero no dijo: "Monique, ¿qué está mal contigo?" Me dio un momento para recobrar el aliento y preguntó: ¿Qué pasó?" Los educadores que trabajaban conmigo dirigían con empatía. Me conocían. Sabían que amaba leer, sabían que amaba dibujar,
they knew I adored Prince. And they used that information to help me understand why my actions, and those of my classmate, were disruptive to the learning community they were leading. They didn't place me on suspension; they didn't call the police. My fight didn't keep me from going to school the next day. It didn't keep me from graduating; it didn't keep me from teaching. But unfortunately, that's not a story that's shared by many black girls in the US and around the world today. We're living through a crisis in which black girls are being disproportionately pushed away from schools --- not because of an imminent threat they pose to the safety of a school, but because they're often experiencing schools as locations for punishment and marginalization. That's something that I hear from black girls around the country. But it's not insurmountable. We can shift this narrative. Let's start with some data. According to a National Black Women's Justice Institute analysis of civil rights data collected by the US Department of Education, black girls are the only group of girls who are overrepresented along the entire continuum of discipline in schools. That doesn't mean that other girls aren't experiencing exclusionary discipline and it doesn't mean that other girls aren't overrepresented at other parts along that continuum. But black girls are the only group of girls who are overrepresented all along the way. Black girls are seven times more likely than their white counterparts to experience one or more out-of-school suspensions and they're nearly three times more likely than their white and Latinx counterparts to be referred to the juvenile court. A recent study by the Georgetown Center on Poverty and Inequality partially explained why this disparity is taking place when they confirmed that black girls experience a specific type of age compression, where they're seen as more adult-like than their white peers. Among other things, the study found that people perceive black girls to need less nurturing, less protection, to know more about sex and to be more independent than their white peers. The study also found that the perception disparity begins when girls are as young as five years old. And that this perception and the disparity increases over time and peaks when girls are between the ages of 10 and 14. This is not without consequence.
sabían que adoraba a Prince. Y usaron esa información para ayudarme a comprender que mis acciones, y las de mi compañero, eran problemáticas para la comunidad educativa que dirigían. No me pusieron en suspensión; no llamaron a la policía. Mi pelea no me impidió ir a la escuela al día siguiente. No me impidieron graduarme; no me impidieron enseñar. Desafortunadamente, esa no es la historia que comparten muchas chicas negras hoy en día en EE.UU. y en el mundo. Vivimos una crisis en la que las chicas negras son desproporcionalmente forzadas a abandonar las escuelas no por la amenaza inminente que representan para su seguridad, sino porque a menudo experimentan las escuelas como lugares de castigo y marginalización. Es algo que escucho de chicas negras de todo el país. Pero no es insuperable. Podemos cambiar esta historia. Empecemos con algunos datos. De acuerdo con el análisis del National Black Women Justice Institute de datos sobre derechos civiles recopilados por el Departamento de Educación de EE.UU., las chicas negras son el único grupo de chicas sobrerrepresentado a lo largo del espectro de la disciplina en la escuela. Esto no significa que otras chicas no sean llamadas a disciplinarse y no significa que otras chicas no estén sobrerrepresentadas en otras partes de ese espectro. Pero las chicas negras son el único grupo representado en exceso por costumbre. Las chicas negras son siete veces más propensas que sus contrapartes blancas a experimentar una o más suspensiones y casi tres veces más propensas que sus contrapartes blancas y latinas a ser enviadas a la corte juvenil. Un estudio reciente del Georgetown Center on Poverty and Inequality explicó parcialmente por qué ocurre esta disparidad cuando confirmaron que experimentan una supresión especial relacionada con la edad, donde son vistas como más adultas que sus iguales blancos. Entre otras cosas, el estudio descubrió que la gente percibe que las chicas negras necesitan menos crianza, menos protección para saber más sobre el sexo y ser más independientes que sus pares blancas. El estudio también descubrió que la percepción de disparidad empieza cuando las chicas tienen cinco años. Y que esta percepción y la disparidad se incrementan con el tiempo y alcanzan su cenit cuando las chicas tienen entre 10 y 14 años. Esto no ocurre sin consecuencias.
Believing that a girl is older than she is can lead to harsher treatment, immediate censure when she makes a mistake and victim blaming when she's harmed. It can also lead a girl to think that something is wrong with her, rather than the conditions in which she finds herself. Black girls are routinely seen as too loud, too aggressive, too angry, too visible. Qualities that are often measured in relation to nonblack girls and which don't take into consideration what's going on in this girl's life
Creer que una chica es mayor de lo que es lleva a un trato más severo, censura inmediata cuando comete un error y culpar a la víctima cuando está lastimada. Puede llevarla a pensar que hay algo mal con ella, en lugar de las condiciones en las que se encuentra. Las chicas negras son habitualmente vistas como muy ruidosas, muy agresivas, muy enfadadas, muy visibles. Cualidades que son a menudo comparadas en relación con chicas no negras y que no tienen en cuenta qué está ocurriendo en la vida de esta chica
or her cultural norms. And it's not just in the US. In South Africa, black girls at the Pretoria Girls High School were discouraged from attending school with their hair in its natural state, without chemical processing. What did those girls do? They protested. And it was a beautiful thing to see the global community for the most part wrap its arms around girls as they stood in their truths. But there were those who saw them as disruptive, largely because they dared to ask the question, "Where can we be black if we can't be black in Africa?" (Laughter) (Applause) It's a good question. Around the world, black girls are grappling with this question. And around the world, black girls are struggling to be seen, working to be free and fighting to be included in the landscape of promise that a safe space to learn provides. In the US, little girls, just past their toddler years, are being arrested in classrooms for having a tantrum. Middle school girls are being turned away from school because of the way they wear their hair naturally or because of the way the clothes fit their bodies. High school girls are experiencing violence at the hands of police officers in schools. Where can black girls be black without reprimand or punishment? And it's not just these incidents. In my work as a researcher and educator, I've had an opportunity to work with girls like Stacy, a girl who I profile in my book "Pushout," who struggles with her participation in violence. She bypasses the neuroscientific and structural analyses that science has to offer about how her adverse childhood experiences inform why she's participating in violence and goes straight to describing herself as a "problem child," largely because that's the language that educators were using as they routinely suspended her. But here's the thing.
o en sus normas culturales. Y no es solo en EE.UU. En Sudáfrica, las chicas negras de la Pretoria High School fueron disuadidas de ir a la escuela con su cabello al natural, sin un procesamiento químico. ¿Qué hicieron estas chicas? Protestaron. Y fue hermoso ver que la mayor parte de la comunidad global apoyó a estas chicas mientras se alzaban en su verdad. Pero hubo quienes las vieron como problemáticas, en gran parte porque se atrevieron a hacer la pregunta: "¿Dónde podemos ser negros si no podemos ser negros en África?" (Risas) (Aplausos) Es una buena pregunta. En todo el mundo, chicas negras lidian con esta pregunta. chicas negras luchan por ser vistas, trabajan para ser libres y pelean por ser incluidas en el panorama de la promesa que ofrece un espacio seguro para aprender. En EE.UU., las niñas, apenas han pasado sus primeros años, son arrestadas en aulas por tener una rabieta. Las chicas de secundaria son separadas de la escuela por la forma en que llevan su cabello al natural o por la forma en que la ropa se ajusta a su cuerpo Las chicas de secundaria experimentan violencia a manos de oficiales de policía en las escuelas. ¿Dónde pueden ser negras las chicas negras sin reprimenda o castigo? Y no son solo estos incidentes. En mi trabajo como investigadora y educadora, tuve una oportunidad de trabajar con chicas como Stacy, una chica a la que me refiero en mi libro "Pushout", que lucha con su participación en la violencia. Ella pasa por alto los análisis neurocientíficos y estructurales que la ciencia tiene que ofrecer sobre cómo sus experiencias adversas en la infancia explican por qué ella participa en la violencia y directamente se describe a sí misma como "chica problemática", en gran parte por el lenguaje que usan los educadores cuando la suspenden habitualmente. Pero esta es la cuestión.
Disconnection and the internalization of harm grow stronger in isolation. So when girls get in trouble, we shouldn't be pushing them away, we should be bringing them in closer. Education is a critical protective factor against contact with the criminal legal system. So we should be building out policies and practices that keep girls connected to their learning, rather than pushing them away from it. It's one of the reasons I like to say that education is freedom work. When girls feel safe, they can learn. When they don't feel safe, they fight, they protest, they argue, they flee, they freeze. The human brain is wired to protect us when we feel a threat. And so long as school feels like a threat, or part of the tapestry of harm in a girl's life, she'll be inclined to resist. But when schools become locations for healing, they can also become locations for learning. So what does this mean for a school to become a location for healing? Well, for one thing, it means that we have to immediately discontinue the policies and practices that target black girls for their hairstyles or dress. (Applause) Let's focus on how and what a girl learns rather than policing her body in ways that facilitate rape culture or punish children for the conditions in which they were born. This is where parents and the community of concerned adults can enter this work. Start a conversation with the school and encourage them to address their dress code and other conduct-related policies as a collaborative project, with parents and students, so as to intentionally avoid bias and discrimination. Keep in mind, though, that some of the practices that harm black girls most are unwritten. So we have to continue to do the deep, internal work to address the biases that inform how, when and whether we see black girls for who they actually are, or what we've been told they are. Volunteer at a school and establish culturally competent and gender responsive discussion groups with black girls, Latinas, indigenous girls and other students who experience marginalization in schools to give them a safe space to process their identities and experiences in schools.
La desconexión e internalización del dolor se fortalece en la marginación. Cuando las chicas se meten en problemas, no deberíamos apartarlas deberíamos acercarlas más. La educación es un factor crítico de protección contra el contacto con el sistema legal criminal. Deberíamos estar construyendo políticas y prácticas que mantengan a las chicas conectadas con su aprendizaje, en lugar de alejarlas de él. Es una de las razones por la que me gusta decir que la educación es un trabajo de libertad. Cuando las chicas se sienten seguras, pueden aprender. Cuando no se sienten seguras, pelean, protestan, discuten, huyen, se bloquean. El cerebro humano está preparado para protegernos de una amenaza. Y mientras la escuela parezca una amenaza, o parte del tapiz del daño en la vida de una chica, estará inclinada a resistirse. Pero cuando las escuelas se convierten en lugares de curación, también pueden convertirse en lugares de aprendizaje. ¿Qué significa que la escuela se convierte en lugar de curación? En primer lugar, supone que tenemos que suprimir inmediatamente las políticas y prácticas que señalan a las chicas negras por su cabello o vestido. (Aplausos) Centrémonos en cómo y qué aprende una chica en vez de vigilar su cuerpo de manera que facilite la cultura de la violación o castigar a los niños por las condiciones en las que nacieron. Aquí es donde los padres y la comunidad de adultos pueden participar. Empezar una conversación con la escuela y animarlos a examinar su código de vestimenta y otras políticas relacionadas con la conducta como proyecto colaborativo, con padres y estudiantes, para evitar intencionalmente el sesgo y la discriminación. Tengan en cuenta que algunas de las prácticas que dañan a las chicas negras no están escritas. Tenemos que seguir haciendo un trabajo interno profundo para abordar los sesgos que informen cómo, cuándo y si vemos a las chicas negras como realmente son, o como nos han contado que son. Sean voluntarios en una escuela y establezcan grupos de discusión competentes a nivel cultural y de género con chicas negras, latinas, chicas indígenas y otros estudiantes que experimenten marginación en las escuelas para darles un espacio seguro para procesar sus identidades y experiencias en escuelas.
And if schools are to become locations for healing, we have to remove police officers and increase the number of counselors in schools. (Applause) Education is freedom work. And whatever our point of entry is, we all have to be freedom fighters. The good news is that there are schools that are actively working to establish themselves as locations for girls to see themselves as sacred and loved. The Columbus City Prep School for Girls in Columbus, Ohio, is an example of this. They became an example the moment their principal declared that they were no longer going to punish girls for having "a bad attitude." In addition to building -- Essentially, what they did is they built out a robust continuum of alternatives to suspension, expulsion and arrest. In addition to establishing a restorative justice program, they improved their student and teacher relationships by ensuring that every girl has at least one adult on campus that she can go to when she's in a moment of crisis. They built out spaces along the corridors of the school and in classrooms for girls to regroup, if they need a minute to do so. And they established an advisory program that provides girls with an opportunity to start every single day with the promotion of self-worth, communication skills and goal setting. At this school, they're trying to respond to a girl's adverse childhood experiences rather than ignore them. They bring them in closer; they don't push them away. And as a result, their truancy and suspension rates have improved, and girls are arriving at school increasingly ready to learn because they know the teachers there care about them. That matters. Schools that integrate the arts and sports into their curriculum or that are building out tranformative programming, such as restorative justice, mindfulness and meditation, are providing an opportunity for girls to repair their relationships with others, but also with themselves. Responding to the lived, complex and historical trauma that our students face requires all of us who believe in the promise of children and adolescents
Y si las escuelas se convierten en lugares de curación, tenemos que eliminar a los policías y aumentar el número de consejeros en las escuelas. (Aplausos) La educación es un trabajo de libertad. Y cualquiera que sea nuestro punto de ingreso, debemos luchar por la libertad. Las buenas noticias es que hay escuelas que trabajan activamente para establecerse como lugares para que las chicas se vean como algo sagrado y querido. La Columbus City Prep School for Girls en Columbus, Ohio, es un ejemplo de esto. Se convirtió en un ejemplo desde el momento que su director declaró que ya no iba a castigar a las chicas por tener "mala actitud". Además de construir... Esencialmente, desarrollaron un espectro sólido de alternativas a la suspensión, expulsión y arresto. Además de establecer un programa de justicia restaurativa, mejoraron sus relaciones alumno-profesor asegurando que cada chica tenga al menos un adulto en el campus al que pueda acudir cuando esté en un momento de crisis. Construyeron espacios a lo largo de los pasillos de la escuela y aulas para que las chicas se reagrupen, si necesitan un minuto. Y establecieron un programa de asesoramiento para dar a las chicas una oportunidad de empezar cada día con la promoción de la autoestima, habilidades de comunicación y establecer metas. En esta escuela tratan de responder a las experiencias adversas de la infancia de una chica en lugar de ignorarlas. Las acercan más, no las alejan. Y como resultado, sus tasas de ausentismo y suspensión han mejorado, y las chicas llegan a la escuela más dispuestas a aprender porque saben que sus profesores se preocupan por ellas. Eso importa. Escuelas que integran las artes y los deportes en su currículum o están desarrollando un programa transformativo, como justicia restaurativa, conciencia plena y meditación, están brindando oportunidades a las chicas de reparar su relación con otros, pero también consigo mismas. Respondiendo al trauma vivido, complejo e histórico que enfrentan los estudiantes requiere que todos los que creemos en la promesa de niños y adolescentes
to build relationships, learning materials, human and financial resources and other tools that provide children with an opportunity to heal, so that they can learn. Our schools should be places where we respond to our most vulnerable girls as essential to the creation of a positive school culture. Our ability to see her promise should be at its sharpest when she's in the throws of poverty and addiction; when she's reeling from having been sex-trafficked
construyamos relaciones, aprendamos materiales, recursos humanos y financieros y otras herramientas que brinden a los niños oportunidad de curarse, para que puedan aprender. Nuestras escuelas deberían ser lugares donde responder a las chicas vulnerables como algo esencial para la creación de una cultura escolar positiva. Nuestra habilidad de ver su promesa debería ser más incisiva cuando está en el camino de la pobreza y la adicción; cuando se recupera de ser víctima de trata sexual
or survived other forms of violence; when she's at her loudest, or her quietest. We should be able to support her intellectual and social-emotional well-being whether her shorts reach her knees or stop mid-thigh or higher. It might seem like a tall order in a world so deeply entrenched in the politics of fear to radically imagine schools as locations where girls can heal and thrive, but we have to be bold enough to set this as our intention. If we commit to this notion of education as freedom work, we can shift educational conditions so that no girl, even the most vulnerable among us, will get pushed out of school. And that's a win for all of us. Thank you. (Applause)
o sobrevivió otras formas de violencia; cuando está en lo más alto, o en lo más bajo. Debemos ser capaces de apoyar su bienestar intelectual y socioemocional si sus pantalones llegan a su rodilla, o al muslo o más allá. Puede parecer una tarea difícil en un mundo tan profundamente arraigado en la política del miedo imaginar a las escuelas como lugares donde las chicas se curen y prosperen, pero debemos ser suficientemente audaces para establecer nuestra intención. Si nos comprometemos con esta noción de educación como trabajo de libertad podemos cambiar las condiciones educativas para que ninguna chica, incluso la más vulnerable de nosotras, salga de la escuela. Y eso es una victoria para todos nosotros. Gracias. (Aplausos)